( WATER LAPPING SOFTLY )
( BOAT KNOCKING SOFTLY AGAINST DOCK )
( WIND CHIME TINKLING )
( VEHICLE APPROACHING )
( VEHICLE DOORS OPENS , CLOSES )
WOMAN 1 : I appreciate it .
WOMAN 2 : I know that your relatives are scattered .
We 'd be happy to come back .
Are you sure you 'll be all right ?
WOMAN 1 : Yes . I 'll be fine . Thank you .
WOMAN 2 : I fly back to Detroit tonight . I 'll get in late ,
but call me if you need to . Anytime .
WOMAN 1 : Mm-hmm . Mm-hmm . I 'll be okay .
WOMAN 2 : Okay . I know you will . Take care , sweetheart .
WOMAN 1 : I will . Bye .
( SIGHS )
( CLOCK TICKING SOFTLY )
( BREATHES SHAKILY )
( FOLK ROCK SONG PLAYING ON SPEAKERS )
( SNIFFLES )
( FOLK ROCK SONG CONTINUES PLAYING )
( SIGHS )
DJ : ( ON VIDEO ) So , raise your hand
if you have better taste in music than the groom .
- ( INDISTINCT CHATTER ON VIDEO ) - Do I see any hands ?
All right , yeah , I see a few .
( FOLK ROCK SONG CONTINUES THROUGH VIDEO )
( INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ON VIDEO )
( LAUGHTER )
( SIGHS DEEPLY )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER AND LAUGHTER )
( CHIMING SOFTLY )
( SIGHS HEAVILY )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
- ( KNOCKING ON DOOR ) - ( GASPS )
( POUNDING ON DOOR )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( INHALES DEEPLY )
- ( ALARM RINGING ) - ( GASPS )
( ALARM CONTINUES RINGING )
( CAR LOCK BEEPING )
( SOFT SQUEAKING )
( GATE SQUEAKING )
( GATE STOPS SQUEAKING )
( BOAT KNOCKING SOFTLY AGAINST DOCK )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
- ( GUNSHOT ) - ( GASPS )
( GASPING )
( SIGHS )
WOMAN 1 : What we 're looking at here are the EOCT scores .
Now , I 'm gonna pick on 10th grade just a little bit
because you 'll see the biggest difference there .
The yellow line , the mustardy one , that 's two years ago .
The blue is last year .
The pink is this year .
( DOOR SLAMS )
WOMAN 2 : ( WHISPERS ) Beth is here .
Give her space .
WOMAN 1 : The pink is this year . So , what happened ?
WOMAN 3 : Teacher-student ratio .
WOMAN 1 : I know , but class sizes are what they are . It 's statewide .
We can 't play the blame game when we 're pulling up the rear ...
BETH : Sorry .
( WOMAN 1 CONTINUES SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
- Hey . - Hi .
I don 't think you had to come . No one would blame you .
I still have grades to enter .
I 'd have done that for you . All you had to do is ask .
It 's all right .
It gives me something to do . For now , anyway .
WOMAN 1 : We don 't wanna be that school .
CLAIRE : You holdin ' up ?
WOMAN 1 : I don 't want to be that principal .
Yeah , I 'm fine .
Just didn 't really sleep well last night .
Can 't believe you slept at all . Especially there .
MAN : We got to show up for them .
PRINCIPAL : Okay . I promised to give you all
a 10-minute break , so let 's go ahead and take that .
Go potty , stretch your legs . There are more donuts in the back ,
courtesy of Mountville Baptist Church , so get you some ,
and be back by 8 : 40 though , on the dot-ish .
- ( KNOCKING ON DOOR ) - WOMAN : Mrs. Parchin ?
Hi .
( SHUTS LAPTOP )
Sorry . I was just ...
WOMAN : Excuse me . I tried to knock , but ...
We met before .
Um , I 'm Hunter 's mom .
- Hunter ... - McLaughlin .
He has you second period .
I 'm Becky McLaughlin . It was a few months ago .
BETH : Right . Of course .
I ... I have so many Hunters this year .
- Oh . How many ? - Hmm ?
Students named Hunter do you have ?
Mm ... Three .
( SMACKS LIPS ) Please , have a seat .
( SIGHS SOFTLY )
I 'm sure you know why I 'm here .
I checked the website .
Hunter got a C in speech .
Oh , right . I think so .
Uh ... Let me check .
- But that 's what it said . - Mm-hmm .
Let me see here .
Uh ... Right , yes .
It looks like he didn 't do his last presentation .
He said that you told him he could make that up .
I did .
Yeah . He , uh ... He didn 't . ( CHUCKLES )
He said he came in last Thursday .
That was the last day of school .
He said that you weren 't here .
Yes , I was out for a few days . It was a personal matter .
Well , he told me he was out the day you presented those projects .
We all have personal matters to deal with sometimes .
( SMACKS LIPS ) Okay . Uh ...
You know what ? Let 's just excuse him
from that assignment . ( CHUCKLES )
Uh ...
( HITS KEY ) There . B.
( CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ) That 's not what I wanted .
Then , uh , what did you want ?
Excuse me ?
When you came in here , what did you want ?
I want to know why my son ...
My husband shot himself in the head last Thursday .
I hadn 't heard .
No , because it 's a personal matter .
So , yeah .
Yeah . If you wanna know ,
he took the boat out on the lake .
He took a handgun that I didn 't even know that we owned .
And pow ! Right in the mouth .
So , which Hunter got what grade
on what high school elective speech class assignment ,
it really doesn 't matter to me right now .
So , you want a B , you got a B.
I ... I apologize .
Oh , you want an A ?
All right . Ta-da ! ( HITS KEY )
A B is fine .
B it is . ( CLICKS )
Anything else I can do for you ?
No .
Thank you .
I 'm so sorry for your loss .
( FOOTSTEPS RECEDING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
- Oh . Hey , Mel . - Hey .
The sky was looking a little mean .
I went ahead and covered the boat for you , just in case .
You didn 't have to do that .
Ah , that 's a goddamn lie if I 've ever heard one .
Just paying it back , that 's all . ( LATCHES GATE )
You and Owen were a couple godsends when Shelly passed .
BETH : Thank you .
( CHUCKLES )
You want me to haul that thing away ?
You just say the word .
It 's okay . I think I 'll leave it .
Sell it with the house .
You thinking about selling ?
Maybe .
I mean , he built it , so I 'd hate to leave it , but ...
MEL : Yeah .
It 's peaceful out here , but it is lonely .
Hey , Mel , were you , uh , shooting this morning
around 7 : 30 or so ?
Didn 't hear anything ? There was a gunshot .
I just figured with the weather getting warmer
- and snakes and all ... - ( CHUCKLES )
I see a copperhead near the house ,
I 'm sure gonna shoot it , but I didn 't today .
Right .
You hear it again , just give me a shout , okay ?
- Okay , I will . - Okay .
- I 'm gonna get back . - Mm-hmm .
BETH : So , this is going to be the office down here ,
and over here will be the kitchen .
- Or maybe it 's here . - ( ELECTRONIC SAW WHIRRING )
( CHUCKLES ) And then ... And then over here we have ,
uh ... ( IMITATES FANFARE )
... biceps . Lots of biceps . ( LAUGHS )
So , that is the husband .
Oh , hey , Owen ! How are you doing ?
- Are you working ? ( CHUCKLES ) - ( WHIRRING STOPS )
You know that we 're paying people to do that , right ?
You don 't have to do it all yourself .
OWEN : Mm-hmm .
BETH : No , no , don 't worry , I 'm not actually filming .
- Mm-hmm ? ( CHUCKLES ) - OWEN : Mm-hmm .
BETH : Well , unless you want me to .
( BOTH LAUGHING ON VIDEO )
OWEN : Let me check .
BETH : No . Stop .
OWEN : Come here .
( BOTH CONTINUE LAUGHING )
- ( REMOTE CONTROL CLICKS ) - ( VIDEO STOPS )
( SIGHS )
( FOLK ROCK SONG BLARING ON SPEAKERS )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( FOLK ROCK SONG CONTINUES PLAYING )
( CELL PHONE CHIMES )
( GASPS )
( MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY )
( GASPING SOFTLY )
( LINE RINGING )
( LINE CONNECTS )
( BETH GASPING )
( BREATH SHUDDERS )
Who is this ?
( STATIC CRACKLING )
( DISTORTED MALE VOICE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
MALE VOICE : ( DISTORTED ) Beth ...
( VOICE BREAKING ) Owen ? Is ...
I know that you can ...
( CRYING ) I can 't hear you . I can 't ...
Yes , you can .
Look out the window .
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( BREATH SHUDDERING )
( GASPS )
( SIGHS )
( SNIFFS )
( DOOR RATTLES )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( CAR LOCK BEEPS )
( SIGHS )
( SNIFFS )
( CHUCKLES QUIETLY )
CLAIRE : What am I looking at ?
BETH : You tell me .
CLAIRE : It 's a picture of you .
BETH : Is it ?
CLAIRE : Yeah .
I mean , nice blouse .
Look ... Look closer .
Is that me ?
Yeah , I think so . I mean , who else would it be ?
That 's what I want to know .
Well , it 's either you or a woman who looks ,
like , a lot like you .
Sweetie , I think that 's you .
Nice blouse , right ? I don 't have one like that .
God , Beth .
Don 't do this to yourself .
It 's you , okay ?
And if it 's not you , then , believe me ,
there are far worse things to find on your husband 's phone
than fully clothed women who look exactly like you .
Mm . Yeah , well , I guess I was his type .
Please . Owen loved you .
You . He worshipped you .
I ...
I mean , from everything you told me ,
you didn 't really give him any reason to roam .
I mean , how do you know he even took those pictures anyway ?
He 's not here to defend himself or explain .
Look , a bunch of us are going out tonight drinking .
The whole department . Well , not Clark , obviously ,
but you should come . Get your mind off things .
We 'll see .
Why were you going through his phone anyway ?
Shit .
Sorry .
That was ... That was a really fucking stupid ,
insensitive thing to say .
I 'm sorry .
I didn 't think we had secrets .
Everybody has secrets .
Don 't let it weigh on you .
Just ...
Just remember your Owen .
Who you fell in love with .
Because whatever else he was , he was that , too .
WOMAN : What 's her name ?
- ( MUSIC PLAYING ) - Maggie Monroe .
Oh , she 'd be my best customer .
She told me I don 't have a knack for teaching anyway .
And she 'd know
' cause she 's an expert on many things .
Jesus Christ .
WOMAN : So , are we going to read the book she gave us ?
Fuck , no . I don 't need 300 pages to tell me
how to " engage and inspire " my students .
Yeah , just let them stand up on their desks or whatever .
- Change their lives . - ( CHUCKLES )
You okay , B ?
Do you guys believe in ghosts ?
Uh ... Ghosts , like , how ?
I do . I believe .
- WOMAN : Really ? - Well , I mean , I don 't not believe .
I think there 's something in my house .
( SNIFFS ) Like a ... a presence .
No way .
I mean , I don 't know .
I feel like there 's something .
Like there 's something watching me . ( CHUCKLES )
And all this weird stuff .
I 'm having these dreams .
I mean , it feels like they 're dreams .
They feel real though when they 're happening .
Like sleep paralysis ?
No .
MAN : Do you know what sleep paralysis is ?
Yes , Gary , I know what sleep paralysis is .
WOMAN : I don 't .
CLAIRE : It 's when your mind 's awake , but your body 's not , right ?
Did you guys see that documentary on ...
GARY : I had this buddy in school who had it .
It 's pretty common to feel like there 's someone else in the room with you
when you 're having an episode .
Like a hostile presence .
What about the opposite ?
GARY : Like a friendly presence ?
No . When your body 's awake , but your mind isn 't .
But isn 't that just sleepwalking ?
BETH : Sure . Sleepwalking .
Could that be contagious ?
GARY : No . Why ?
Owen used to sleepwalk .
I remember that .
A year or two after he built the house , it just started .
Now you 're doing it ?
BETH : Yeah .
That 's weird .
( CHUCKLES )
How long were you married ?
Uh ... Oh .
( SMACKS LIPS )
Let me do the math .
( CHUCKLES )
BETH : Fourteen years .
This next one , this next one would have been 15 .
WOMAN : Wow .
You were married young .
Little bit . Little bit .
I mean , you spend so much time
in the same space with someone ,
it 's gonna feel like they 're there .
Even when they 're not .
CLAIRE : But who knows , right ? I mean , who 's to say
what happens once we
" shuffle off this mortal coil , what dreams may come " ?
GARY : No . No Shakespeare until next fall .
Are you really gonna cheer me up with the suicide soliloquy ?
Fuck . Oh , my God .
Oh , my God , I didn 't ... I 'm so sorry .
( LAUGHING )
- I 'm joking . - ( GARY CHUCKLES )
I 'm joking .
You shouldn 't be joking about that .
Heather ...
Oh ...
Did you seriously not know that anything was wrong ?
Gary ! Jesus , you guys ...
No , I don 't mind .
No , I didn 't know .
I 'm the one who struggled with that stuff . Depression .
Dark thoughts .
He 's the one that kept them at bay .
Maybe it got to him .
I don 't know . Maybe I infected him with my bullshit .
No , no . It ...
- It doesn 't work like that . - BETH : No ?
( GARY SIGHS )
Did he leave a note ?
CLAIRE : Okay .
- I 'm sorry . - GARY : She wants to talk about it .
CLAIRE : I think we 're done with this conversation .
He did .
- CLAIRE : Beth ... - ( CHUCKLES )
HEATHER : God .
You keep it in your purse ?
Okay . ( CHUCKLES )
- ( HEATHER CLEARS THROAT ) - ( EXHALES DEEPLY )
( CLICKS TONGUE )
" You were right .
" There is nothing .
" Nothing is after you .
" You 're safe now . "
That 's it .
That 's it ?
No " XOXO , your loving husband . "
Nothing .
What does that mean ?
Not a clue . Not a fucking clue .
Other than I was living with a crazy person
and didn 't know it .
Makes you wonder though , doesn 't it ?
What else didn 't I know ? ( CHUCKLES )
I want to know .
Okay . I think that it 's time we get you home .
Sure . I mean , I wouldn 't wanna keep him waiting .
CLAIRE : Okay .
Let 's go .
BETH : Okay , fine , let 's go .
CLAIRE : Good night , guys . Thank you .
- Okay . - Let 's go . I got you .
- ( INDISTINCT CHATTER ) - ( MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING )
( DOOR SLAMS )
CLAIRE : Wow , you 've really made some progress on the place .
BETH : Mm-hmm .
You want a brandy ?
CLAIRE : No , Beth . I don 't want a brandy .
- And I don 't want you to have one either . - BETH : Okay .
I don 't even like it that much .
Haven 't acquired the taste .
Come on , upstairs with you .
No . I 'm sleeping here .
Okay . Do you want me to stay ?
Mm-mm . You 've got kids .
It 's fine . I could just ...
I can call Bob . I told him I was gonna be out late .
I could just call him and ...
No . Mm-mm .
Well , you should come over soon .
For dinner or something . I 'll get Bob to cook for us .
I don 't like you here all by yourself .
( BETH CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
I lied .
About the letter .
( LAUGHING ) You asshole ! Oh , my God !
Oh , my God , you totally has us going . I thought that was real .
Did you see Gary 's face ?
It is real .
I meant that I lied about having no idea what it meant .
You know , I ...
I died back in Tennessee . Did I tell you that story ?
Mm-mm .
Seventeen , high school .
Friend was driving ,
and we flipped over the side of a mountain .
Pancaked . ( SLAPS HAND )
( CHUCKLES LIGHTLY )
Lungs were crushed . They had to airlift me out .
Heart stopped . Whole deal . Four minutes .
Oh , my God .
Afterward , when everyone would ask me when they found out ,
like , " What was it like ? What did you see ? "
And I didn 't want to disappoint them , so I 'd say ...
" I don 't know . I don 't remember . "
But I remember .
Owen was the only person I ever told .
There 's nothing .
What do you mean , " Nothing " ?
( CHUCKLES DRYLY )
I wish I could tell you something .
A light at the end of the tunnel .
There 's just tunnel .
( CHUCKLES )
If it 's any consolation , Owen was never convinced .
Yeah , we agreed about most things , but not that .
Not what comes after . He wanted to believe in a better place .
And he almost made me believe it , too .
But you can 't unknow what you know .
" You were right . There is nothing .
" Nothing is after you .
" You 're safe now . "
He told me I was right .
Now I 'm not so sure .
He said you were safe . Safe from what ?
I guess we 'll never know , will we , Claire ?
Do you really believe in ghosts ?
CLAIRE : No . I was just being nice .
BETH : Mm .
You are . You 're very , very nice .
( SOFTLY ) Sure you don 't want me to stay ?
( SLEEPILY ) Maybe just till I go to sleep .
( BREATHES DEEPLY )
- ( GASPS ) - MALE VOICE : Beth .
( GASPING )
Beth . Wake up .
The door .
- Beth , wake up . - ( GASPING )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( WIND CHIME TINKLING )
BETH : Claire ?
MALE VOICE : The door .
You wanna say something ? Talk to me !
( PANTING )
( SNIFFS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WOMAN GASPS )
Hey !
- ( GASPING ) - ( WOMAN 2 YELPING )
Hey ! Hey !
- Hey ! - ( WOMEN WHIMPERING )
( GASPING RAPIDLY )
What ? ( WHIMPERING )
( GASPING )
Wait ! No ! No !
( WOMAN 3 CRIES OUT )
( GASPS )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( GASPING )
MALE VOICE : ( WHISPERS ) The boat .
BETH : ( WHIMPERS ) What did you say ?
MALE VOICE : The boat .
( WHIMPERS )
( WOOD CREAKING )
( BETH GASPS )
( BREATHING NERVOUSLY )
( WATER BUBBLING SOFTLY )
( WHISPERS ) Owen ?
Are you really here ?
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
If you 're with me , show me .
- ( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ) - ( DOCK CREAKING )
( BREATH SHUDDERING )
- ( WIND GUSTS ) - ( GASPING )
Is that really you ?
- ( THUD ) - ( GASPS )
( WATER SLOSHING )
MALE VOICE : It 's a dream .
You 're dreaming .
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
( BREATH SHUDDERS )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( GASPING SOFTLY )
( PUTS CELL PHONE DOWN )
( GASPS )
( SNIFFS )
( FLIES BUZZING )
( DOG PANTING )
Beth ?
Hey .
What are you doing out here ? Taking a hike ?
Uh , no . No , I 'm just looking for something .
Can I help ?
Uh-uh .
What you looking for ?
Uh ... A house .
- A house ? - Mm-hmm .
No houses out here . It 's all county forest land .
Can 't build on it .
Right . I 'm just being silly .
I thought I saw something last night , like a ...
Looked like a light in a window , so ...
A house ?
Mm-hmm .
Anyway , it 's doing me good to get some air .
So , if you don 't mind ...
As a matter of fact , I do .
Sorry , what ?
You 're not well , Beth .
You 've been through a lot lately . More than you deserve .
And for my own peace of mind , if nothing else ,
I 'd rather not have you tromping around out here in the woods on your own .
You should be with your friends and family .
Do you have anybody ?
Hey . How about my place for lunch ?
- I 'll make sandwiches . - ( INHALES SHARPLY ) Mm-hmm .
Yeah , that sounds nice .
Maybe in a little while though , okay ?
( FLIES BUZZING )
( EXHALES DEEPLY )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
Anyone here ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKS )
- ( QUIET FOOTSTEPS ) - ( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
( CREAKING STOPS )
( PANTING )
Mel ?
MEL : Hold on !
( CONTINUES KNOCKING )
Okay .
- What the fuck is this ? - What ?
What the fuck is this ?
How should I know ?
Bullshit . You were trying to keep me out of the woods .
Because I 'm worried about you .
- What was he building ? - What ?
There is a house . Our house . My house .
Now , what the fuck was he building ?
I don 't know . I never saw a house .
I only saw him wandering around out there
in the middle of the night from time to time .
What ? And you didn 't tell me ?
He asked me not to .
( SCOFFS )
( SLAMS DOLL ON TABLE ) Mel .
- Look , Beth ... - ( SIGHS )
I don 't think you 're equipped to handle this right now .
( LAUGHS SARCASTICALLY )
Oh . ( SCOFFS )
Tell me everything that you know .
I caught him once .
Like I caught you this morning .
Taking that same route around the lake .
( MEL SIGHS )
He had a woman with him .
I thought it was you , so I called out , and when she turned ...
It wasn 't .
( SIGHS ) No .
He came by that night .
Pounding at my door . Late .
In a real bad way .
Alcohol on his breath . Mud on his hands and clothes , like he 'd fallen .
And I know how it sounds now ,
but I believed every word he said .
And ? What did he say ?
That he had urges .
Shameful urges ...
that he was rightfully ashamed of , that he was trying to shake .
Said he 'd found a way to keep them at bay .
What kind of urges ?
You 'll forgive me if I didn 't feel the need to ask .
( INHALES DEEPLY )
Look . Don 't think I haven 't wrestled with this , okay ?
But I swear on Shelly 's grave
that I never saw anything like that again . Ever .
I wanted to tell you so many times ...
( SIGHS HEAVILY )
but he just seemed good after that .
- You both seemed so good . - ( SCOFFS )
Well , I guess you were wrong .
He left a hole in your life
and you 're desperate to fill it . That 's what this is .
Look , if ...
All I can say is that , if I 'm allowed to say anything ,
is that you don 't need to fill it with something dark .
You 're closer to death than you 've ever been .
Well , that 's not exactly true .
( PANTING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WHIMPERS )
( BREATH SHUDDERS )
( KICKS BOX AWAY )
( TYPING )
( BETH BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GRUNTS )
( WOOD CREAKING )
- ( CREAKING CONTINUES ) - ( LIGHT , MUFFLED FOOTSTEPS )
- ( SOFT THUD ) - ( CREAKING STOPS )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
BETH : Okay .
( SWITCH CLICKS )
( SIGHING )
( SNIFFS )
( EXHALES DEEPLY )
( SOFT CREAK )
- ( HEAVY CREAK ) - ( GASPS )
Come back .
( PANTS ) Come back ...
( CAR LOCK BEEPS )
( SHOPKEEPER 'S BELL TINKLES )
Just one sec .
I 'm not actually buying these . I just have a quick question .
Uh , my husband bought these from you ,
and I 'm just wondering if you could tell me
whether he bought anything else ,
or whether he had something on hold ? Something like that ?
Um , we don 't really keep records like that .
Okay . Could you tell me when ?
When he bought these ?
Maybe you have an inventory ?
- Not like that . - Right .
Could you tell me other books by this author ?
Tsk .
- Let 's see ... - ( BETH CLEARS THROAT )
It 's Dyson .
Think you probably want Sturgis , but okay ...
( SOFT THUD )
BETH : Hi .
Hi .
You work here ?
I do . Can I help you with anything ?
Mm-mm .
I 'm Beth .
Beth Parchin .
Madelyne .
I think you knew my husband .
- No , I don 't ... - Owen . Owen Parchin .
( MADELYNE CLEARS THROAT )
There are pictures of you on his phone .
Jonah ?
It 's all right . You don 't have to call for help .
I 'm not gonna ... ( CHUCKLES )
I mean ...
the matter 's been resolved ...
I guess .
- Oh . - Yeah .
He 's dead .
What ?
Suicide . ( IMITATES GUNSHOT )
Oh , my God .
Just in case you had any dates planned , or ...
Mm-mm .
- It wasn 't like that . - Oh .
Well , then would you mind telling me what it was like ?
( HESITATINGLY ) Sure . Um ...
He came in a few times every year ,
and he was always friendly .
We flirted some , and he started coming more after that .
We had a few drinks , and that was it .
Take your hair down .
- What ? - Your hair . Ponytail .
Lose it . Take it down .
Why ?
Well , because you slept with my husband , and I 'm asking you nicely .
I didn 't ...
( SCOFFS )
( INHALES DEEPLY )
I didn 't sleep with him .
Honestly , I barely knew him .
MAN : ( ON TV ) For centuries , stories of the ...
She said she barely fucking knew him .
CLAIRE : What did you say ?
Same . I said , " Same here , kid . "
( LAUGHS )
Do you believe her ?
What ? About them not fucking ?
Yeah .
I do .
Well , that 's something .
Nothing good .
I mean , fucking , I get . Fucking makes sense .
There were others . Our neighbor saw him with someone .
Really ?
Yes . And I looked on his computer ,
and there are tons of pictures ,
like half a dozen women .
They all look a little bit like me , but not quite .
So if he wasn 't fucking them ,
what the hell was he doing ?
( KNOB CLICKING )
I had this dream the other night .
It was our house , but not .
It was backwards ,
and I saw him with someone ...
Stop . Stop it .
Stop going through his stuff .
Nothing you find is gonna help you right now .
Am I not being clear ? He had a secret life .
Are you really gonna stand there and lecture me
about his posthumous right to privacy ?
CLAIRE : I understand you 're experiencing these things ,
but I 'm worried about you .
Maybe take a step back .
( SIGHS ) I don 't know .
( BETH BREATHES DEEPLY )
I felt him .
I felt my husband .
" You were right . There 's nothing . "
Why would he say there 's nothing ? He didn 't believe that .
CLAIRE : Beliefs change .
Look at you . ( CHUCKLES )
You 're the most skeptical person I know ,
and here you are , telling me that your house is haunted .
Yeah , I mean , ( CLEARS THROAT ) when you put it like that ,
it does sound kinda silly .
Don 't go home .
Get away from the lake for a while .
You can stay here , even .
You can stay as long as you want .
It 's not finished .
( CLAIRE SIGHS )
Not everything gets finished .
You may never know what he was thinking .
He 's gone . You 're not .
You still have a life to live .
( CHUCKLES )
No , you 're right .
I could use the distance .
I 'll go pack a few more things . Get a bag .
Book into a room for a couple nights .
- I can 't tell if you 're being serious . - BETH : I am .
And you 've made some excellent points . Really .
I love you .
Just call me later , okay ?
I will .
( CAR LOCK BEEPING )
- ( CAR DOOR CLOSES ) - ( ENGINE STARTS )
( SWITCHES CLICK )
I 'm leaving .
Tonight , I guess .
So , if you 've got something to say to me , you better say it now .
You hear me ?
( SETS GLASS DOWN )
Motherfucker . ( SCOFFS )
( LAUGHS )
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
Hey !
( NERVOUSLY ) Sorry . I didn 't think you were home .
I 'm home .
I don 't think I should be here .
How did you know where to go ?
Well , I 've been here before .
( SCOFFS )
I probably should have told you earlier at the bookstore ,
but , uh , honestly , you freaked me out a little .
BETH : Sorry about that .
No , I get it . Totally .
I probably would have done the same thing .
It 's funny , really ,
I laid down for a minute after work ,
and I had this dream .
I dreamed I was you .
Well , I was me , but I was you , too ,
and something was chasing you , and it was all around you .
Well , us .
But did it get us ? ( CHUCKLES QUIETLY )
I 'm not sure . That 's when I woke up .
Afterwards , I couldn 't stop thinking about you .
I figured there 's something you should know .
- Stuff that happened . - Phew .
I told you I didn 't sleep with your husband .
Yeah , you can use his name . He wasn 't " my husband " to you .
Right .
Well , I meant it .
I didn 't sleep with him .
But I would have . I thought we would , but ...
He came by one afternoon
after I was getting off ,
and he invited me here , like a ... like a day trip .
And normally , I wouldn 't have gone ,
but he was smart , and sweet , and ...
I don 't know . I just kind of felt safe with him , you know ?
I do .
Right .
So , yeah , um , he took me here
and , uh , we had a drink .
We walked to the lake , and he showed me the other house ...
Wait . You 've seen it ?
Well , it 's not much to see , but he was really proud of it , though .
I mean , giddy , almost .
Showing me around from room to room .
And then , he showed me this weird statue , and he asked me to hold it .
And you did ?
What exactly did he do to you ?
MADELYNE : Nothing .
He held me ...
sort of .
He put his chin on my shoulder and ...
Look , I know it sounds weird saying it out loud ,
but at the time ,
it felt really nice .
Having someone close to you .
Feeling them there .
I ...
I felt him shake .
And he was crying a little , and I didn 't know what to do .
What did he do to you ?
I kissed him . He kissed me back and ...
It was very sweet at first .
So , I ... I ...
didn 't stop him when he put his hands on my back .
And I didn 't stop him when he put his hands on my neck .
Until he started squeezing .
Oh , my God .
I probably misread him , you know ? I just ...
Everybody has a different barometer for that kind of thing .
Did he hurt you ?
God , no !
I asked him to stop , and he stopped .
But do you think he would have ?
But he didn 't .
He drove me home .
He said it was his fault , not mine .
That he was tired and confused ,
and he didn 't know what was him ,
and it wasn 't working anymore .
He was afraid he couldn 't hold it back .
Hold what back ?
I don 't know exactly .
But in the end ,
he said he knew what he had to do .
He had to end it for good .
Look ...
I just wanted to tell you .
He clearly felt guilty about cheating on you .
( SCOFFS )
That 's what he was talking about , right ?
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( ENGINE STARTS )
( BOTTLE CLINKS )
( POURS DRINK )
( PANTING )
( CONTINUES PANTING )
We need to talk .
I 'm not leaving until we do .
You called , I came .
Don 't you wanna talk to me ? ( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
You talked to her .
( SING-SONGY ) I 'm here . I 'm still here .
Wherever you are ...
come and get me .
( LOUDLY ) Just come get me !
( LAUGHING )
( PANTING )
Okay . ( CHUCKLES )
( GRUNTS )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( GASPS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GASPING )
Fucking ... ( PANTING )
( GRUNTS )
( CRYING )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( SNIFFLES )
Okay . Okay . Come on , pick up the phone .
AUTOMATED VOICE : Claire Woodward ...
Fuck !
... is not available . At the tone ,
please record your message . ( BEEPS )
I 'm sorry . Hey , it 's , uh ... it 's late .
And , uh ...
I should have listened to you .
I did something that I shouldn 't have .
I went across the lake , and I saw something .
( VOICE BREAKING ) I saw something so ...
I don 't even know if it 's real or not .
( CHUCKLES DRYLY )
I know my husband .
I know who he is ,
and I refuse to believe that he would have ...
( INHALES SHARPLY ) I don 't know .
( SIGHING HEAVILY )
I wish that you were here .
I wish that it were morning .
( PANTING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( FOLK ROCK SONG BLARING ON SPEAKERS )
( MUFFLED FOLK ROCK SONG CONTINUES PLAYING )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( GASPING SOFTLY )
( MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY )
( WHIMPERS ) No .
Stop it .
Owen ?
( BREATHES SHAKILY )
( CRYING ) Where are you ?
I just ...
I don 't understand .
Please come back .
( SOBBING HEAVILY )
Oh , God .
I miss you so much .
( SIGHS )
( GASPS )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( GLASS SQUEAKING )
( SIGHS )
( WATER DRIPPING )
( GASPING SOFTLY )
Is this real ?
Are you really here ?
( GASPING HEAVILY )
( GRUNTS SOFTLY )
Hold me . Hold me .
( GASPS SHARPLY )
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
You 're really here ?
- MALE VOICE : Yes . - ( GASPS )
( PANTING )
I 'm here .
( GASPING SOFTLY )
Owen ?
No .
I 'm not Owen .
( WHIMPERS )
( GASPING )
Fuck . Fuck .
( GLASS SHATTERS )
( GASPING RAPIDLY )
( RATTLING )
( DOOR THUDS )
( WHIMPERS SOFTLY )
( GASPING )
( BOTH GASP )
( WOMAN CRIES OUT )
( GASPING )
- ( OWEN GRUNTING ) - ( WOMAN YELPING )
( WHISPERS ) No , stop it .
( WOMAN GASPING )
( BOTH GRUNTING )
- ( WOMAN YELPS ) - ( GASPS )
( WOMAN WHIMPERING )
( WOMAN CRIES )
( OWEN GRUNTS )
( GASPS )
( CHOKING )
( BREATHING WEAKLY )
( GLASS CRACKS )
( GROANS SOFTLY )
( WHISPERS ) Hide .
BETH : What ?
- ( WOMAN WHIMPERS ) - ( GASPS )
( OWEN GRUNTING )
( OWEN BREATHING HEAVILY )
- ( HEAVY CREAK ) - ( GASPS )
( HEAVY CREAKING )
( GASPING )
( GASPS )
( HEAVY CREAKING )
( DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY )
( HEAVY CREAKING CONTINUES )
( GASPING HEAVILY )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( YELPING )
( GRUNTING )
- ( WOMAN SCREAMING ) - ( OWEN GRUNTING )
( YELPING )
( MUFFLED WOMAN SCREAMING )
( OWEN SOBBING )
BETH : Owen ?
( GASPS )
( GROANING )
( GASPING )
( O HOLY NIGHT PLAYING FAINTLY ON SPEAKERS )
( BETH BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WHISPERING ) You left .
What ?
The night we met .
You 're not Owen .
I 'm what you felt when your heart stopped .
No . I felt ...
MALE VOICE : Nothing .
Do you remember ?
You saw me .
And I 've been with you ever since .
What did you do to my husband ?
MALE VOICE : I went to him .
I whispered in his ear
over and over .
To send you back .
( BREATHES SHAKILY )
But he wouldn 't .
He sent me them instead .
He tricked you .
For a while .
( GASPS )
( GRUNTS )
Shit .
- MALE VOICE : Stop . - ( GASPS )
( WHIMPERS )
- ( GRUNTS ) - Don 't fight .
No !
- ( BETH GRUNTING ) - Beth .
( GROANING )
( STRAINED GRUNTING )
( YELLING )
( CHOKING )
( CONTINUES CHOKING )
( GRUNTS , GASPS )
( STOPS CHOKING )
( EXHALING DEEPLY )
( WIND CHIME TINKLING )
Beth ?
Hello ?
Beth , are you here ?
I 'm coming up .
Beth ?
( SHOUTING ) Beth !
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Where is he ?
( BETH BREATHING RAGGEDLY )
Gone .
But you already knew that .
( PANTING )
What the fuck ?
Oh , my God .
Beth ! ( ECHOING )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
MALE VOICE : He thought he could protect you .
He was wrong .
You were right .
( SHOUTS ) Beth !
Beth !
MALE VOICE : There is nothing .
There is only me .
Come back to me .
( BETH BREATHES SHAKILY )
CLAIRE : Beth !
It doesn 't matter .
Let go .
Come back to me .
CLAIRE : Beth !
Beth !
Oh , my God .
( CLAIRE GRUNTING )
CLAIRE : I 'm right here .
Keep your head up . This way .
( CLAIRE AND BETH GRUNTING )
( BETH GASPING )
- Is she okay ? - CLAIRE : I don 't know .
What happened ?
I don 't know . I don 't know . ( SOBS )
Beth ? Are you here ? Are you here ?
( GRUNTS ) I 'm here , I 'm here .
I 'm here .
CLAIRE : I got you .
( SOBS )
CLAIRE : I got you , I got you .
I 'm right here . I 'm here .
( BOTH PANTING TIREDLY )
Just breathe .
You 're safe now .
You 're okay , you 're gonna be okay .
MEL : What is it ?
There 's nothing there .
( BETH BREATHING SHAKILY )
BETH : I know .